KATARINA SKARBOVA

<u>LinkedIn</u> k.skarbova@gmail.com

+46 793 417 946

UX DESIGNER



SKILLS

User Research

Ethnographic Fieldwork Interviews/Observations SQLite

User Interface Design

Rapid Prototyping Balsamiq InDesign Adobe XD/Figma

Creative programming

HTML/CSS/GIT JavaScript Adruino/Processing

LANGUAGES

full proficiency

Slovak, English, Swedish

limited proficiency **German, Serbian, Latin**

I am a User Researcher & Experience Designer with a master's degree in applied ethnography, currently studying UX Design at EC Utbildning in Malmö. I am passionate and skilled about uncovering actionable insights through user research and testing. I look for an UX Design internship in spring 2021 to sharpen even my prototyping skills on real design projects.

EDUCATION

UX DESIGNER | EC Utbildning

2020 - 2022

Gained competence in: UX business practices and communication,
 Design sprint projects, Design Thinking and Agile methods,
 Programming for UX-production, User Interface Design,
 Information Architecture.

INTERACTION DESIGN | Malmö University

january 2020 - may 2020

 Gained competence in: Digital and physical product design, Analyzing interactivity, Gathering requirements for a user-centred design, Sketching, Personas, Paper prototyping, Developing functional hi-fi prototypes, Writing UX reports.

DESIGN THINKING, HUMAN COMPUTER INTERACTION & USER EXPERIENCE COURSES | Interaction Design Foundation 2018 - present

 Gained competence in: Creating user interface designs based on principles of human cognition, Design for desktop, mobile and physical devices, creating holistic and sustainable customer value.

APPLIED CULTURAL ANALYSIS | Lund University

2015 - 2017

 Gained competence in: ethnographic field work - interwieving, observation, field notes, theoretical concepts of human centred reserach, project management for organisational development.
 See more details on the next page - my internship experience as Cultural Analyst.

INTERESTS

Actively practicing hot yoga

Reading about psychology

Couchsurfing (now on hold)

VOLUNTEERING

STUDY MENTOR

Swedish Red Cross 2018 - 2020

INTERNATIONAL MENTOR

Lund University 2016

PROMOTER

League Against Cancer 2010 - 2012

WORK EXPERIENCE

FLORIST

Mobilia Blommor | Malmö | 2016 - 2020

 Learned to handle stress situations, deepened my insights into customer behavior and service and improved Swedish language.

CULTURAL ANALYST

Uppåkra Archaeological Centre | Uppåkra | 2016

 Responsible for project leadership, communication with the client, recruiting informants, qualitative interviews, group interviews, context mapping research, participant observations, transcribing material, defining problem, ideation (personas, scenarios), designing deliverable (storyboards), writing reports, presenting results for the client.

RECEPTIONIST

Studentinfo, Akademiska Föreningen | Lund | 2015 - 2017

Responsibile for providing advice to students in person, via email
or phone, sell campus clothes, accessories and tickets to student
events and oversee inventory and office supply purchases.

RECEPTIONIST

Pantheon Technologies | Bratislava | 2013 - 2015

 Responsibible for handling incoming calls, emails and reservations, organize internal events, complete check requests and purchase orders, assist HR with hiring procedures.

CERTIFICATES

SWEDISH LANGUAGE PROGRAM

Malmö University | 2017 - 2018

CAMBRIDGE ADVANCED ENGLISH

Certificate | 2015

VERBAL COMMUNICATION FOR MANAGERS &

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

University of Seattle, Bratislava | 2015

EU DRIVING LICENSE

Issued | 2012

LinkedIn

k.skarbova@gmail.com